<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<db>
  <question no="1">
		<body>The acronym 'ACID' in database management system stands for
		</body>
		<options>
			<a>Atomicity, Consistency, Isolation, Durability </a>
			<b>Atomicity, Consistency, Isolation, Distributable</b>
			<c>Atomicity, Consistency, Integrity, Durability</c>
			<d>Atomicity, Concurrency, Isolation, Durability</d>
		</options>
		<answer name="a">The ACID stands for Atomicity, Consistency, Isolation, Durability.
		</answer>
		<category>DBMS</category>
	</question>
	<question no="2">
		<body> The term 'Atomicity' in database management system states that 
		</body>
		<options>
			<a>Each transaction is "all or nothing" i.e. if one part of the transaction fails, the entire transaction fails, and the database state is left unchanged. </a>
			<b>Each transaction is "all or something" i.e. if one part of the transaction fails, the other parts of the  transaction many not fail, and the database state is left changed.</b>
			<c>Primary key and foreign key should be atomic.</c>
			<d>Primary key may be atomic, but foreign key can not be atomic.</d>
		</options>
		<answer name="a">The term 'Atomicity' in database management system states that each transaction is "all or nothing" i.e. if one part of the transaction fails, 
						 the entire transaction fails, and the database state is left unchanged.
		</answer>
		<category>DBMS</category>
	</question>
	<question no="3">
		<body> The property 'Isolation' in database management system ensures that
		</body>
		<options>
			<a>two or more transactions can not be run concurrently if they are using same database resources.</a>
			<b>the concurrent execution of transactions results in a system state that would be obtained if transactions were executed serially, i.e. one after the other.</b>
			<c>the effects of an incomplete transaction might be visible to another transaction.</c>
			<d>ensures that any transaction will bring the database from one valid state to another.</d>
		</options>
		<answer name="b">The property 'Isolation' in database management system ensures that the concurrent execution of transactions results in a system state that would be obtained 
						 if transactions were executed serially, i.e. one after the other.
		</answer>
		<category>DBMS</category>
	</question>
	<question no="4">
		<body> The property 'Durability' in database management system means that
		</body>
		<options>
			<a>when a transaction has been committed, it should remain so, even in the event of power failure, system crash or errors.</a>
			<b>when a transaction has been committed, it should remain so only, if there is no power failure, no system crash or no errors.</b>
			<c>when a transaction has been committed, it should remain so only, if there is no power failure, no system crash.</c>
			<d>when a transaction has been committed, it should remain so only, if there is no errors.</d>
		</options>
		<answer name="a">The property 'Durability' in database management system means that when a transaction has been committed, it should remain so, even in the event of power failure, 
						 system crash or errors.
		</answer>
		<category>DBMS</category>
	</question>
	<question no="5">
		<body>The 'Entity Integrity Rule' in RDBMS states that
		</body>
		<options>
			<a>A table may or may not have a unique and not null primary key.</a>
			<b>A table can have a null primary key.</b>
			<c>Every table must have either a primary key or a foreign key.</c>
			<d>Every table must have a unique and not null primary key.</d>
		</options>
		<answer name="d">The 'Entity Integrity' in RDBMS rule states that every table must have a unique and not null primary key.
		</answer>
		<category>DBMS</category>
	</question>
	<question no="6">
		<body>The 'Referential Integrity Rule' in RDBMS states that
		</body>
		<options>
			<a>A foreign key can not contain a null value, it always contains only values from a parent table's primary key</a>
			<b>If a primary key is null, the corresponding foreign should also be null.</b>
			<c>A foreign key can contain either a null value, or only values from a parent table's primary key.</c>
			<d>Every must have either a primary key or a foreign key.</d>
		</options>
		<answer name="c">The 'Referential Integrity Rule' in RDBMS states that A foreign key can contain either a null value, or only values from a parent table's primary key.
		</answer>
		<category>DBMS</category>
	</question>
	<question no="7">
		<body>Which one of the statements is incorrect about a Relation(Database Table) following the 1NF(First Normal Form)?
		</body>
		<options>
			<a>Two tuples(rows) in a relation(table) can be identical.</a>
			<b>Each attribute(column)value must be a single value(atomic).</b>
			<c>The order of the attributes(columns) is significant.</c>
			<d>Each attribute(column) must have a unique value.</d>
		</options>
		<answer name="a"> According to 1NF, A database table can not have duplicate rows.
		</answer>
		<category>DBMS</category>
	</question>
	<question no="8">
		<body>Which one of the following statements is not true if a database relation(table) is in 2NF?
		</body>
		<options>
			<a>The relation(table) is in 1NF.</a>
			<b>All non key attributes(columns) are functional dependent on the key attributes(columns).</b>
			<c>The relations(tables) that have a single attribute for a key are automatically in 2NF.</c>
			<d>The relation(table) contains no transitive dependencies.</d>
		</options>
		<answer name="d">A relation in 2NF can contain transitive dependencies. 
		</answer>
		<category>DBMS</category>
	</question>
	<question no="9">
		<body>Which of the following statements are true if a relation(table) is in 3NF?
		</body>
		<options>
			<a>The relation(table) is in 1NF.</a>
			<b>The relation(table) is in 2NF.</b>
			<c>The relation(table) is in BCNF(Boyce-Codd Normal Form).</c>
			<d>The relation(table) contains transitive dependencies.</d>
		</options>
		<answer name="cd"> A relation in 3NF is also in 1NF, and 2NF, but not in BCNF. Also 3NF relation contains no contains transitive dependencies.
		</answer>
		<category>DBMS</category>
	</question>
	<question no="10">
		<body>Find the incorrect statement(s) out of following?
		</body>
		<options>
			<a>A relation which is in 4NF is also in 1NF, 2NF, 3NF and BCNF.</a>
			<b>A relation which is in 4NF is also in 1NF, 2NF, 3NF but not in BCNF.</b>
			<c>A relation which is in 4NF is also in 1NF, 2NF, 3NF and BCNF.</c>
			<d>A relation which is in 5NF is also in BCNF.</d>
		</options>
		<answer name="b"> The statement "A relation which is in 4NF is also in 1NF, 2NF, 3NF but not in BCNF" is false.
		</answer>
		<category>DBMS</category>
	</question>
</db>
